<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-15T01:25:19+00:00</updated><id>https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CommonSense America</title><subtitle>Helping Americans defend the ideas that make America great with truth and grace.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Tale of Two Trails</title><link href="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/12/07/a-tale-of-two-trails.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Tale of Two Trails" /><published>2020-12-07T22:43:11+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-07T22:43:11+00:00</updated><id>https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/12/07/a-tale-of-two-trails</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/12/07/a-tale-of-two-trails.html">&lt;p&gt;There are 2 paths. 2 sides, each with a different story. As you walk down the paths, it becomes clear that many have walked where you do now. Many have fought the same battle. The battle to save the lost art of discussion, the art of communication before it became sour, before it was overruled by inconsequential aggressiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first path is led by beautiful things. Unity, peace, and acceptance. It is warm and bright, filled with the grace of God and his never ending love. Leaves fly by, signaling hope and prosperity. There are footprints on the ground, going both ways, as it is safe to walk either direction, as each end leads back to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second path is dim. God’s presence still radiates from this path, but it’s colder. The sun doesn’t shine here. The ground is rough, with roots of resentment overgrown throughout the trail. The trees are bare, stripped of their leaves that once told countless stories. The chilled winds whirl past with an essence of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;urgency. Footsteps are still embedded into the ground, but they only go one way. It seems that the ones who walked this path don’t return. Silenced. This is the path of hate, where ideas are halted, where civil conversation has been shut out, replaced with antagonizing tones and words sharp enough to cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thick fog is up ahead. It surrounds the entirety of the paths, making the traveler unsure of which trail he walks. The paths are getting narrow now. The fog is getting heavier. We are lost, but safe, as our hearts are still being guided by God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fog will end soon, leaving the traveler to continue their journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the fog ceases, which path will you be on?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Burris</name></author><summary type="html">There are 2 paths. 2 sides, each with a different story. As you walk down the paths, it becomes clear that many have walked where you do now. Many have fought the same battle. The battle to save the lost art of discussion, the art of communication before it became sour, before it was overruled by inconsequential aggressiveness.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/uploads/peter-burris-picture.PNG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/uploads/peter-burris-picture.PNG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Christian’s Obligation to the Government</title><link href="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/30/a-christian-s-obligation-to-the-government.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Christian’s Obligation to the Government" /><published>2020-11-30T18:23:14+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-30T18:23:14+00:00</updated><id>https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/30/a-christian-s-obligation-to-the-government</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/30/a-christian-s-obligation-to-the-government.html">&lt;p&gt;“I would be the first to advocate obeying just laws. One has not only a legal but a moral responsibility to obey just laws. Conversely, one has a moral responsibility to disobey unjust laws. I would agree with St. Augustine that “an unjust law is no law at all.” -Martin Luther King Jr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, a point of contention in the church has always been centered around one’s duty to obey the state. All throughout history, this has led to division among Church leaders. From early Christians obeying the Roman emperor to modern day pastors closing their churches at the wishes of government officials, one does not have to look very hard to see this division arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Christians debate and discuss this topic, it is important to glean our wisdom and understanding from what the scriptures say on this issue since this is where Christians are supposed to derive their authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at the scriptures at first, one might perceive a conflicting message with Ecclesiastes 8:2-4 expressly saying,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Obey the king’s command, I say, because you took an oath before God. Do not be in a hurry to leave the king’s presence. Do not stand up for a bad cause, for he will do whatever he pleases. Since a king’s word is supreme, who can say to him, “What are you doing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This passage is incredibly direct. It leaves little room for dissent. If one only saw this passage, it could lead one to believe the role of a Christian is to be a clone of the state and government. If those verses were not clear enough on a Christians duty to the government, Solomon goes on,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whoever obeys his command will come to no harm, and the wise heart will know the proper time and procedure.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears that the Biblical stance on obeying government authority is clearly on the side of obedience and allegiance to whatever governmental body holds power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Paul, a scholar of the Old Testament would later write in Romans 13, “Let everyone be subject to the governing authorities, for there is no authority except that which God has established. The authorities that exist have been established by God. Consequently, whoever rebels against the authority is rebelling against what God has instituted, and those who do so will bring judgment on themselves”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this may seem like a cut and dry case of blind submission and obedience to those in positions of power, the Bible has some conflicting stories to contest with these sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example the characters of Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego in the book of Daniel from the Old Testament. In Daniel 3, a story is told of three young Jews in exile in Babylon. King Nebuchadnezzar of Babylon made a giant gold image of himself and proclaimed everyone must bow and worship it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These three Jews, Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego, had the courage to not only defy their King but also the commands of Ecclesiastes 8. It would appear that by denying to worship Nebuchadnezzar they were defying God’s commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would make sense as it was clearly written “Whoever obeys his (the king’s) command will come to no harm.” Yet when they were receiving punishment for refusing to bow and worship the king, the Lord directly interfered and saved them from the wrath of the king.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surely he would not do such a thing for three young Jews receiving the fitting punishment for their actions. Surely those being punished for disobedience to God would not be delivered from their earthly consequences by God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s now look to the Hebrew Midwives in Egypt, commanded by Pharaoh to kill all Hebrew boys that they delivered. According to Solomon and Ecclesiastes, killing the little children would not be wrong since it was the order of the king. According to what he had written, it would be wrong for them to not kill the children and disobey the orders of Pharaoh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is unless what Solomon and later Paul was writing about was not blind undying allegiance to the government. Unless the relationship of a Christian to government were to be designed more as that of a child to a babysitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by this? God makes it clear the rules by which he wants his children to be governed by. He lays a clear roadmap of morality and virtue that governments are to lead and rule by. It is clear that these basic principles of morality are supposed to be reflected in the governing laws of any government institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commands of the Bible to be good citizens and obey the King particularly deal with commands outside of the clear dictates of the word of God. It is clear from the coming teaching of Christ that one must “give to Caesar what is Caesar’s”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put: any value or principle issued by the government not expressly enumerated against in the Bible must be obeyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is through this principle that the Hebrew midwives were found righteous; Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego vindicated; and Paul writing Romans 13 from jail for disobedience to the government justified in his teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle for governance laid out in the Bible is like that of instructions a mom might provide to a babysitter left in charge of her children. She gives rules, a few basic guidelines, but then she turns over her authority to the babysitter and commands her child to follow the babysitter’s additional rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the babysitter then seeks to deliberately disobey the specific guidelines set forth by the mother, it is not only the right, but the duty of the child to obey the higher authority, his mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is through this lens that Christians must see their relationship to government. It was an institution established by God for our benefit, but should that institution ever seek to deliberately coerce behavior antithetical to the values of the Bible, it is the duty of Christians to obey their higher authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is through this that righteous children of God have been vindicated over the centuries. From Martin Luther sparking the reformation, Bonhoeffer seeking to kill the sole leader of Germany, Reverend Martin Luther King Jr writing from jail, and Corrie ten Boom lying to protect the Jews in her care. It is by remembering who ultimately has our allegiance and bestowed the governing bodies with their authority that Christians can maintain a healthy relationship with government.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Grant May</name></author><category term="Masks" /><category term="Government" /><category term="Christianity" /><category term="civil disobedience" /><summary type="html">“I would be the first to advocate obeying just laws. One has not only a legal but a moral responsibility to obey just laws. Conversely, one has a moral responsibility to disobey unjust laws. I would agree with St. Augustine that “an unjust law is no law at all.” -Martin Luther King Jr</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/uploads/profile-picture.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/uploads/profile-picture.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Does God call Christians to participate in Politics?</title><link href="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/does-god-call-christians-to-participate-in-politics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does God call Christians to participate in Politics?" /><published>2020-11-29T01:26:03+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-29T01:26:03+00:00</updated><id>https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/does-god-call-christians-to-participate-in-politics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/does-god-call-christians-to-participate-in-politics.html">&lt;p&gt;Politics is often seen as a separate entity from our entire lives. Politics is not merely a restraint on our corruption after the fall, but it is a central element to our humanity seen from God’s original creation and design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In society, it has become common to draw a strict separation between “politics” and the “culture.” Yet, we have seen that separating politics from culture only encourages immorality and injustice. It gives more aid, power, and comfort to those who treat the role of politics as a cynical power game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Christians, we should be as involved in politics and government as much as all other realms of life. Founding Father, John Jay, our first Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, says, “Providence has given to our people the choice of their ruler, and it is the duty, as well as the privilege and interest of our Christian nation to select and prefer Christians for their rulers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of distancing ourselves from any connection with a civil government, it should be our greatest calling, task, and duty. When Jesus was on earth, He resided and lived under the oppression of an imperial dictatorship. Mark 12:17 declares, “Jesus said to them, “Render to Caesar the things that are Caesar’s, and to God the things that are God’s.” And they marveled at him” (Mark 12:17, ESV). Jesus was sharing that we have a responsibility to engage in civil matters. We have the God-given opportunity to select leaders and place them into office. Either way, some set of values or moral standards are going to govern and control a nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, as Christians we should desire to get involved in selecting our leaders who will govern according to God’s principles and formulate policy that will be honoring to Him. Every single time a legislature enacts legislation, it has imposing morality. Laws against stealing and thievery impose morality over the honest and the dishonest. Laws that go against prostitution impose sexual morality. A law declaring something legal or illegal is a declaration of something moral or immoral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legislation is established upon morality and ultimately morality is built upon religion. John Adams, our second president, declared: “We have no government armed with power capable of contending with human passions unbridled by morality and religion…Our constitution was made only for a moral and religious people. It is wholly inadequate to the government of any other.” God cares about politics, because He cares about everything. Often times we hear Christians say, “God doesn’t care about politics.” Yet this phrase undermines God, and constrains His power. Psalm 24:1 declares, “The earth is the Lord’s and the fulness thereof, the world, and those who dwell therein.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lord doesn’t limit himself ! He is involved, planning, and making decisions before they even come to pass! The blessing is that God has called us to stand for Him and His righteousness through politics and whatever comes to pass in politics now or in years to come.. God is still in control and we can be confident that His will has been done! God bless America, because God is still in control!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emma Dieterle</name></author><category term="Christianity" /><category term="Political Involvement" /><category term="Bible" /><summary type="html">Politics is often seen as a separate entity from our entire lives. Politics is not merely a restraint on our corruption after the fall, but it is a central element to our humanity seen from God’s original creation and design.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Dangers of Packing the Courts</title><link href="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/the-dangers-of-packing-the-courts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dangers of Packing the Courts" /><published>2020-11-29T01:22:29+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-29T01:22:29+00:00</updated><id>https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/the-dangers-of-packing-the-courts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/the-dangers-of-packing-the-courts.html">&lt;p&gt;With the tumultuous 2020 election coming to a close, there has been substantial talk about the possibility of the Biden administration ‘packing the courts’. The fact that the Biden campaign has refused to answer whether they would pursue this sort of action if elected is rightly concerning to many. To be clear, packing the courts is the process by which a president nominates more justices with aligning political beliefs than empty seats to the courts. If such action were to be taken, the checks and balances enshrined in the Constitution as well as the representative nature of the government would be undermined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The framers of the Constitution of the United States set in place three branches of government in order to check and balance each other, namely, the legislative, executive, and judicial branches. The Legislative branch, as established in Article 1 of the Constitution, is an elected branch that reserves the power of creating the legislation. The Executive branch, according to Article 2, is also elected by the people and tasked with enforcing the laws. Lastly, as described in Article 3, the Judicial branch is the only branch that is not elected by the people. Rather, it is nominated by the executive branch and tasked with interpreting the laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When operating as the framers intended, the three branch system is effective in preventing tyranny and balancing power between the branches of government. The legislative and executive branches were designed to insert their will into their work because they were elected and, thus, representatives of the people. However, since the Judiciary is not elected, they are not intended to insert their will into their work. Alexander Hamilton wrote in the Federalist papers number 78 that the Judiciary “has no influence over either the sword or the purse; no direction either of the strength or of the wealth of the society; and can take no active resolution whatever. It may truly be said to have neither force nor will, but merely judgment; and must ultimately depend upon the aid of the executive arm even for the efficacy of its judgments.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was how the framers intended the Judiciary to be. However, throughout the years, the courts have been given more power and the system of nominating justices has become largely political. Unfortunately, this means that some will try to take advantage of this power and potential political gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Packing the court was last attempted by Franklin Delano Roosevelt during the Great Depression. Roosevelt was having difficulties passing extensions to the New Deal as there was significant opposition on the Supreme Court. To combat this, Roosevelt proposed the Judicial Procedures Reform Bill of 1937. This bill stated that for every justice over the age of 70 years and 6 months who had served on the Supreme Court for over 10 years, the president could nominate a new justice. This would allow Roosevelt to nominate up to six additional justices, and as a result, pack the courts with left-leaning and New Deal-supporting justices. This came just one year after Roosevelt had referred to court packing as “a distasteful idea” at a Cabinet meeting. Roosevelt’s attempt to bypass Constitutional protections was quickly and fervently opposed by multiple justices and elected officials on both sides of the political aisle. However, this debate still continues today. Since such a process has never occurred in American history, many Americans are unaware of the dangers of packing the courts. However, court packing creates a direct threat to the protections against tyranny and mob rule manifested in the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability of a president to nominate additional justices gives the Executive branch political leverage over the Judicial branch. If a president were to pack the court with partisan and corrupt justices, the justices could essentially create legislation from the bench to benefit their party. In this situation, the political party in charge of the executive branch can receive favorable rulings in virtually every Supreme Court case. Congress, who directly represents the people, would have diminished power because the courts could potentially be used to overturn unfavorable laws. This would leave the Judiciary and president to implement whatever they please, despite the will of the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Biden campaign has yet to declare whether they would pack the courts, the answer as to if they should is clear. The destruction it would cause to the founding principles, protections, and representative nature of the United States would be incredible, and thus, must not be pursued.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allie Fenter</name></author><category term="Supreme Court" /><category term=" Leftism" /><category term="Court Packing" /><summary type="html">With the tumultuous 2020 election coming to a close, there has been substantial talk about the possibility of the Biden administration ‘packing the courts’. The fact that the Biden campaign has refused to answer whether they would pursue this sort of action if elected is rightly concerning to many. To be clear, packing the courts is the process by which a president nominates more justices with aligning political beliefs than empty seats to the courts. If such action were to be taken, the checks and balances enshrined in the Constitution as well as the representative nature of the government would be undermined.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Us versus Them</title><link href="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/us-versus-them.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Us versus Them" /><published>2020-11-29T00:49:51+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-29T00:49:51+00:00</updated><id>https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/us-versus-them</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/2020/11/29/us-versus-them.html">&lt;p&gt;“As traditional tribes of place evaporate, we rally against common enemies so we can feel part of a team. No institutions command widespread public trust, enabling foreign intelligence agencies to use technology to pick the scabs on our toxic divisions. We’re in danger of half of us believing different facts from the other half, and the digital revolution throws fuel on the fire.” Thus begins Ben Sasse’s book Them: Why We Hate Each Other and How To Heal. While I don’t agree with everything Senator Sasse states in his book, I completely agree with him that we have reached a scary point in American politics. People are now willing to say and do things to those they deem their political enemy that decades before would have been unthinkable. There are two key factors contributing to this tribalist mentality: the erosion of our social fabric and the inability to have respectful conversations with members on the other side of the aisle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first factor helping to create a toxic political divide is the erosion of our social fabric. America is unique and it always has been unique. She has had her fair share of problems and challenges, but one thing that has almost always been true is Americans were on this crazy ride together. Throughout American history, social institutions played a vital role in the lives of Americans. From church to boy scouts; choir to bowling club, Americans have valued social interaction and the art of being neighborly. It was common to know most people who lived in your town or neighborhood and to check in on them and talk to them. However around the age of information and globalization, a new style of living crept into American life. The great Francis Schaeffer called this the “age of personal peace and affluence”. Materialism and apathy slowly captured the hearts of many Americans and these social institutions started to crumble. Fewer and fewer Americans participated in the social functions that made America unique. This meant less and less social interaction and more and more selfishness. Less interaction with people who are different than us allowed us to surround ourselves with like minded individuals, creating an echo chamber. Americans no longer participated in events where they would have to talk with people of different beliefs than themselves. This creates a lack of understanding for ideological opponents and creates an us versus them mentality. When you cannot admit wrong on your side but are willing to point out the wrong of your opponents all day, you have reached a point where cooperation and unity are difficult to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second factor helping to create a toxic political divide is the inability to have respectful conversations with members on the other side of the aisle. Once our social institutions crumbled, one was less likely to have conversation with those of opposing viewpoints. These conversations, which were once so vital to the American way of life, were no longer happening. Most Americans simply tried to ignore political differences and not bring them up. They believed an anti confrontational approach would be best. While it does not make enemies, avoiding hard topics won’t get anyone anywhere. By avoiding discussing truth, some Americans feed the lie that there can be many truths. Others however, eager for confrontation, seek not to have respectful, constructive conversations, but they rather prefer to try and “score points” for their ideological tribe. Instead of walking into a conversation ready to learn and reconcile beliefs, they approach their ideological enemy ready to do war. Some of those seeking confrontation do use actual arguments and logic, but they do not approach the conversation with humility; others however, for fear of being annihilated in an ideological warfare choose to not argue their policy platform and ideas but rather their opponents character. They choose to smear and defame the character of who they perceive to be their opponent. If they can make others believe that they are a bad person, they no longer have to deal with the ideas of their opponent. The digital revolution increased this problem exponentially. Before when making a character argument, one would be responsible for the words they said; however, now anyone can take to the internet, hide behind a fake name, and assassinate the character of their ideological opponent. Hiding behind a screen emboldens cowards from every basement across the nation to say things that would never be said if we were actually having conversations in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, there are two key factors contributing to the tribalism mentality: the erosion of our social fabric and the inability to have respectful conversations with members on the other side of the aisle. Now that we have arrived at this point, the obvious question remains: where do we go from here. The way I see it, we have two options: continue down this road where we do not befriend those with opposing beliefs and seek instead to destroy them, or we can back track. We can turn around and realize that maybe we didn’t have this whole thing right. Maybe it is worth sometimes being told we are wrong and walking away with the truth than always being right. Maybe it is worth passing up the opportunity to humiliate someone based on their beliefs and instead show them the truth with kindness. Maybe we can start investing in unique American institutions again. Maybe we can focus less on the labels that divide us and more on the ones that unite us. After all, we are all Americans.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Grant May</name></author><category term="Tribalism" /><category term="Unity" /><category term="Heal" /><summary type="html">“As traditional tribes of place evaporate, we rally against common enemies so we can feel part of a team. No institutions command widespread public trust, enabling foreign intelligence agencies to use technology to pick the scabs on our toxic divisions. We’re in danger of half of us believing different facts from the other half, and the digital revolution throws fuel on the fire.” Thus begins Ben Sasse’s book Them: Why We Hate Each Other and How To Heal. While I don’t agree with everything Senator Sasse states in his book, I completely agree with him that we have reached a scary point in American politics. People are now willing to say and do things to those they deem their political enemy that decades before would have been unthinkable. There are two key factors contributing to this tribalist mentality: the erosion of our social fabric and the inability to have respectful conversations with members on the other side of the aisle.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/uploads/profile-picture.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.commonsenseamericaus.com/uploads/profile-picture.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>